Now we're going to talk about character development.
How do you develop a character?
Although there are things that go into a character, there is the appearance of a character.
There is the age of a character that functions into character development, there are the relationships of a character, and there is the character's purpose.
Why is the character on stage?
This works for some of the supporting parts.
What is the purpose of the character?
What do they function to do?
And there's also a biography.
Some of the details of the character's life, some of the things that are not necessarily so apparent, like their age or how tall they are, their body type, things like that.
These are more things that you would have to get to know someone with.
So these are some of the ways that you can develop a character.
You can say maybe they are untidy: their hair is always messy and their shirt is always sticking out of their clothes; their shoes are always almost falling apart; they are maybe 40 years old.
So then we get to see that they had a decent amount of life experience.
The relationships: They tend to hang out at a bar a lot; they know a lot of people that work at the bar, so that's where a lot of their relationships come in.
Their purpose, their purpose.
Maybe they are the confidant of the main character.
Maybe the main character tells them their dreams; explore some of the aspects of what's going on with them, maybe their biography.
Maybe they had the same dream as the main character but they didn't achieve it.
They have advice to impart for the main character on how to achieve that dream.
These are ways that we can develop a character.
Find ways to create that life on stage.